這是本仇恨的書 用來報復每個外強中乾的
It's a book of hate, to wreak revenge on every pompous
爬上卡特韋夫人門檻的小爬蟲
trembling worm who taps at Mrs Castaway's door.
你是...?      蘇糖就是我的姓名
And you are?        Sugar is all there is to my name.
就算會被折磨死 我也要治好病
I am going to get well. Even if it kills me.
人生得一知己 一世難求啊
Kindred spirits like yourself are difficult to find.
我對蘇糖的專屬佔有權
Exclusive patronage of Sugar by me.
我願意
I am willing.
你的人生從今以後就不同了
Your life is going to be very different from now on.
我不是瘋女人
I am not a mad woman!
我預料她很快就會崩潰
I expect a full collapse very shortly.
我的上帝 威廉·拉克漢 你得對我更好點了
My God, William Rackham. You'll keep me better than you do now!
我的天使
My angel...
終於來了
..come at last.
紅玫瑰白玫瑰 第二集
-==破爛熊樂園傾情奉獻==-
本字幕僅供學習交流，嚴禁用於商業用途
他睡得正甜
He sleeps so sweetly,
就像個孩子 自以爲安全
like a child, imagining that he is safe.
-=破爛熊字幕組=-
翻譯：tpring LOVEKEICO
校對：tpring
時間軸：馬老師的學生眞可憐
正體中文轉製及校對：Uriel
可我也有我的夢
But I have my dreams also.
夢想着報復每一個奪走我純眞的男人
Dreams of revenge against the men who took my innocence.
(本片含有部分粗口)
This programme contains some strong language
(以及性場面)
and scenes of a sexual nature.
你知道嗎 我好多年
You know, it's been years
沒在一個女人身邊過一整夜了
since I've slept beside a woman all night.
我得起了 還得回家看看
But I must get up. I have to look in at home.
你肩上的擔子可眞重
You have so many responsibilities.
對了 信函照我們討論的改了嗎?
Oh, did you make those changes we discussed to the letter?
該死的黃麻商人
Damn jute merchants.
又不敢惹他們翻臉      都改好了
Can't afford to fall out with them.        All done.
這是什麼臭味?
What is that terrible smell?
現在我的鼻子可靈敏了
My nose is very sensitive at the moment.
如果連德爾斐熏衣草
If it can distinguish between Lavandula delphinensis
和寬葉熏衣草都能區分 那當然也能聞出
and Lavandula latifolia then it can certainly detect...
是狗屎
Uh! Dog's mess.
哦 威廉 眞對不起
Oh, William, I'm sorry.
聖基爾斯這裏髒亂不堪
St Giles is filthy.
我們能有別的地方相會就好了
I do wish there was somewhere else we could meet.
我眞不願意把你拖到這個瘟疫窩來
I hate dragging you to this plague pit.
眞的 有時我覺得要是
You know, I sometimes think it would be a miracle
我25歳還沒染上霍亂就是奇蹟了
if I'm not carried off by the cholera by the time I'm 25!
別説了
Don't say that!
得了 只不過是萍水之交的女人 然後呢
Really, one forms the slightest attachment to a woman, then...
信給我
The letter.
威廉 對不起 我是開玩笑的
William, forgive me, I was joking.
還是別開的好
Well, I wish you wouldn't.
天啊 拉克曼太太 您可眞忙活
Goodness, Mrs Rackham. You have been busy.
你知道這些是什麼嗎 克拉拉?
Do you know what this is, Clara?
請柬?
invitations?
這是諒解
It's forgiveness.
社會對我敞開大門了
Society opening its doors.
我也要參加社交季了
I am to be included in the Season.
布利德樓夫人都發來了 你看
Even Lady Bridgelow, see?
安菲特太太還請我下週去用茶
And Mrs Amphlett has invited me to tea next week.
世界要變了 克拉拉
A great change is in the air, Clara!
一切都會好起來的
Everything is going to be all right!
福克斯太太      亨利
Mrs Fox.        Henry.
希望我沒打攪到您
I hope I do not inconvenience you.
説哪裏話 請原諒這麼亂
Not in the least. Forgive all this,
我家被救濟社當成倉庫了
I've become the Rescue Society's unofficial warehouse.
哦 抱歉
Oh, excuse me.
這就是你今天沒看見我去教堂的原因
This is why you did not see me at church today.
恕我冒昧 你的女傭在哪?
Forgive me, where is your maid?
我週末讓她放假回家 照顧她祖父去了
I let her go home on the weekends to care for her grandfather.
這麼説 家裏就你和我
So, we are alone in the house?
這樣...合適嗎?
Is that...quite decent?
恐怕可可對我刺激非常大
I'm afraid I find cocoa terrifically stimulating.
我們太容易受誘惑了
We are so easily seduced.
是嗎?
Are we?
就在上週 我回家途中
Just last week, I was on my way home
剛拜訪完一個非常悽慘的家庭
from visiting a particularly wretched family.
我又疲憊 又沮喪 連路也懶得走了
I was tired, discouraged, and I didn't want to walk.
恍惚之間
And before I knew what I was doing,
我就進了地下鐵道 在大地中飛速穿行
I was in the underground railway, speeding through the earth,
滿心只想着自己的愉悅
mindless of anything except my own pleasure.
這一切只要一枚六便士
And all at the cost of a sixpence.
天啊
Goodness.
我沈醉其間 甚至坐過了站
I enjoyed it so much, I missed my stop.
世界會這麼毀了的 亨利
This is how the world will end, Henry.
基督之敵就是我們的慾望
The Antichrist is our own desires.
你起得眞早
You are the early bird.
我要出門辦點事
I have some errands to run.
好吧 反正你閒得很
Well, you've time on your hands.
亨特先生好久沒來了 對吧?
We haven't seen much of Mr Hunt lately, have we?
多久了 一個星期?
What is it? A week now?
亨特先生很忙
Mr Hunt is a busy man.
看來是這樣
Oh, so it seems.
不過忙些什麼 我就搞不清了
Although with what exactly, I'm never certain.
等他下次來 你問問他啊
Well, you can ask him, next time he comes.
分手的時候別吃虧就行 記住了?
Just so long as you parted from him on good terms, hmm?
還照老辦法
As always.
不過我們怕什麼?
But what do we care?
我知道爐邊客棧的人可想你了
I know you're much missed at the Fireside.
還記得你小時候 我們玩的那個遊戲嗎?
Do you remember the game we used to play when you were a baby?
在最寒冷的冬夜
On the coldest winter nights,
我溜進你房間 你睡得正熟
I'd creep in to your room while you were sleeping,
緊緊裹着毯子 我就...
all cuddled up in your blanket, and I'd...
把它掀掉
pull it off!
你記得嗎?
Do you remember?
我就把它掀掉
I'd pull it off
然後説
and I'd say,
「上帝就愛這麼做!」
"That's what God does!"
上帝就愛這麼做
That's what God does.
早安
Morning.
刀尖抵上了柔軟的皮肉 我卻猶豫起來
'The dagger tip touched tender flesh and yet I hesitated.
他不是所有男人中最壞的一個嗎?
'Was not this man worse than all the rest?
他不是背叛了我的信任
'Had he not abused my trust
把我扔回汙穢之中了嗎?
and cast me back into the pit of filth?
可我還是挿不下去
'Yet I could not thrust it home.
我收起我忠實的匕首
'I put away my trusty blade,
取來毒藥和最柔軟的布
fetched poison and the softest cloth.'
做個好夢 我的愛人
Sweet dreams, my love.
拉克漢太太 你的祕方是什麼?
Mrs Rackham, what is your secret?
我的祕方?      新的蒸氣浴療法嗎?
My secret?        Some new spa, perhaps?
你氣色簡直太好了
You're looking most terribly well.
哦 沒有 沒有 安菲特太太
Oh, no, no, no, Mrs Amphlett.
我正在想 你的樣子
Well, I was just thinking that you look
也比上次見面改善了很多呢
quite remarkably different from the last time I saw you.
這麼瘦 我都認不出你了
So thin! I hardly recognised you.
承蒙誇獎      哪裏呀 我都嫉妒了
You are very kind.        Not at all, I'm envious.
我遵守嚴格而簡單的養生食譜
I swear by a strict but simple regime of
只有清水和青豆
water and green beans,
如果頭暈 再加一口牛尾湯
and if I am feeling dizzy, a mouthful of oxtail soup.
不過湯必須非常剋制
But the soup must be very well strained.
我得記住 不 我得抄下來
I shall remember. No, I shall write this down.
我得提醒你 一開始
I should caution you that at first
你可能感到頭痛 虛弱
you may experience debilitating headaches.
我已經飽受頭痛折磨了
I am already a martyr to headaches!
我們一邊談話 我就一邊感到可怕的抽痛
As we speak, I'm prey to a terrible throbbing.
其實你不必這樣受苦
But there is no need for you to suffer as you do.
瞧這個...
Here, look...
不舒服時 我就吃上兩片...
On bad days, I take a couple of these...
加一劑高弗雷鎭靜劑 (常用藥 主料爲鴉片)
..with a dose of Godfrey's Cordial.
找你的藥劑師要
Ask your pharmacist.
醫生知道了會對你長篇大論...
Your doctor would give you a lecture on them...
可是相信我
but trust me -
你會連自己都不認得的
you will hardly know yourself.
這樣可眞愜意
Well, this is pleasant.
一起用餐
A meal together.
你提議我們一起用餐的
You suggested we have a meal together.
對 是我提的
Yes, I did.
祝你好胃口
Bon apetit.
什麼 親愛的?      是青豆
What is it, dear?         Green beans.
不 你剛剛在微笑
No, you were just smiling.
哦 威廉...
Well, William...
其實是因爲...
..the fact is...
我有個守護天使
..I have a guardian angel.
你是説克拉拉?
Are you referring to Clara?
不 一個眞正的守護天使
No, a real guardian angel.
她守望着我們
She watches over us.
我時時刻刻都感到她在身邊
I feel her about me all the time.
我覺得她是從健康修院來的
I think she's from the Convent of Health,
就是我睡着了會去的那個地方
you know, the place I go when I'm asleep.
我沒發現你出去啊 親愛的
I wasn't aware you were going anywhere, dear,
你睡得好好的
when you were sleeping.
那裏的修女都是眞正的天使
The nuns there are really angels.
我很久前就在懷疑了
I suspected that for a long time.
好在現在有證據了
But what a relief to have proof!
證據?
Proof?
對 我朝她揮手 她也朝我揮手
Yeah, I waved to her and she waved back.
你不餓嗎?
Are you not hungry?
他來了
He's here!
快去叫他上來啊
Well, go on, send him up.
他要你下去
He wants you to come down.
他在跟卡特韋説話
He's talking to Castaway.
蘇糖
Sugar.
恐怕亨特先生受夠我們的房子了
I'm afraid to say, Mr Hunt has had enough of our house.
我太遺憾了 亨特先生
I'm sorry to hear that, Mr Hunt.
看來亨特先生對你另有安排
It seems Mr Hunt has other plans for you.
我一直在想你
I have missed your company.
離開你我也很難受
It's been difficult getting away.
艾格尼絲開始産生幻覺了
Agnes is seeing things.
幻覺?
Seeing things?
在街上看見天使
Angels in the street.
還有誰在?
Who else is here?
這是什麼?
What is this?
這是你的
This is yours.
也是我的
And mine.
我再也不能忍受你住在
I couldn't bear the thought of you living in that
那個汙穢的貧民窟了
filthy part of town any longer.
銀行會寄給你生活費
The bank will send you an allowance.
這是第一筆
First payment is here.
你完全獨立了
You will be independent.
説句話啊      哦 上帝
Say something!        Oh, dear God!
想你的鏡子了嗎?
Will you miss your looking glass?
我還看自己做什麼 不是有你看着我了嗎?
Why do I need to look at myself when I have you to look at me?
我吩咐了卡特韋夫人 你房裏的東西都別動
I've instructed Mrs Castaway that nothing in your room be touched
等你去取
until you remove it.
我離開她傷心了嗎?
Did she seem sorry to see me go?
一點都沒有
Not in the least!
那老錢婆纔不會放過一筆好交易呢
The old trout knows a good deal when she sees one.
不過你不用再管她了
But you need not worry about her any more,
也不用管從前的人了
nor anyone from your past.
你有了新的人生
You have a new life,
在這裏 和我一起
here with me.
你的書全都拿走啦?
Taken all your books, I see?
別忘了那個盆
Don't forget your bowl.
不錯的盆呢      我不需要了
Good bowl, that.        Well, I won't need it.
新家有個浴缸
There's a bath at the new place.
你的牀單誰洗呢?
Who'll take care of your sheets?
我自己洗唄
I will, I suppose.
那我可少了一件活了
That's me out of a job then.
告訴你 我覺得 克里斯托弗...
You know, I was thinking, Christopher, that...
我可以偶爾回來 和你一起唸書
I could come back sometimes and you and I could read together.
我會回來找你的
I will come back for you.
你要離開我們啦
You're leaving us then.
過了這麼多年
After all these years.
老天知道 當年爲了擺脱你我費了多大勁
Lord knows I tried hard enough to be rid of you once.
什麼毒藥沒往身上招呼過
No brew so toxic I didn't inflict it upon myself,
多燙的洗澡水沒泡過
no bath so scalding I didn't immerse myself in it.
你就是死不了
You were indestructible!
希望我將來還這樣吧
Let's hope I remain so.
十九年前 我們開始一起生活
19 years since we embarked on this life together.
六年前 你輕輕走到我房間裏説
Six since you tiptoed to my room and told me
有位先生給我取暖來了
there was a gentleman come to keep me warm.
母親 那我...
Well...Mother, I...
當然 親愛的
Of course, dear.
不耽誤你了
Nothing to hold you here.
和亨特先生過好日子去吧
Onward and upward with Mr Hunt!
(英格蘭銀行)
Bank of England
(拉克曼香水公司 - 目錄)
Rackhams' Perfumery Co
恐怕我們要分開一陣了
I'm afraid I won't see you for a while.
我得在丹地待到週四
I'm in Dundee until Thursday,
週五我約了波德利和阿什韋
and then I've Bodley and Ashwell on the Friday.
我會盡早擺脱他們回來
I will get away from them as early as I can.
你會在這裏等我嗎?
You'll be here?
我還能去哪呢?
Where else?
你相信嗎 艾格尼絲那天晚上也要出門
Believe it or not, Agnes is also out that night!
布利德樓夫人要帶她去皇家阿爾伯特劇院
Lady Bridgelow is taking her to the Royal Albert Hall.
哎呀 那可是大進歩啊
Goodness, that's a step forward.
嗯
Yeah.
她覺得歩子太大了 可我説服了她
Too big a step, she thought, but I persuaded her.
威爾第的新劇
The new Verdi.
多虧契斯曼
Thank goodness for Cheesman.
至少我知道她能平安到達 平安回來
At least I know she'll get there and back in one piece.
我跟你説過新馬車伕吧?
I-I told you of this new coachman?
我幫你看的他的推薦信
I checked his references for you.
當然了
Of course you did.
她眞了不起 想想她受了那麼多委屈
She's been marvellous really, considering how she has suffered.
也許艾格尼絲比你想的要堅強
Well, perhaps Agnes is stronger than you imagine.
我是説布利德樓夫人
I mean Lady Bridgelow.
她不盲從大多數
She knows better than most the,
社會渣滓的殘酷偏見
the cruelty of petty social stigma.
別低估你自己的魅力 威廉
Don't underestimate your own allure, William.
她是位現代貴族 不害怕結交
She is a modern aristocrat, not afraid to associate herself
生意人的親屬
with those who have dealings with people in trade.
我佩服她這一點
I admire her for that.
錢還夠嗎?
Do you have enough money?
足夠了
Plenty.
去華威吃點好的 點他們的鯛魚
Make sure you eat properly go to the Warwick, order the bream.
「我是個有家室的體面人啊」
"But I am a respectable family man,"
他喊着 我用利刃劃破他的襯衫
he cried as I cut through his shirt with my razor-sharp shears.
(香氛調配)
Composing Perfumes
打發點吧 小姐 打發點吧?
Spare a coin. Miss, spare a coin?
我只是回來拿藥粉的 順便來看看你
I just came to pick up my powders, I thought I'd call in.
哦 你眞好
Oh, that's nice.
在瑪麗勒本弄不到藥粉?
Can't get your powders in Marylebone then?
我敢説肯定有
Well, I daresay I could,
可我不知去哪找...該問誰
but I don't know where or...or who to ask.
在那邊沒有朋友?
Got no friends up there?
沒有那種朋友
Not that kind.
這麼説他對你還不錯?
He's fair to you, then, is he?
衣服不代表什麼 蘇糖
Clothes don't mean nothing, Sugar.
他可能用壁爐釬子打你 逼你舔鞋什麼的
Might beat you with a poker or make you lick his shoes for all that.
不 他不是那種人
No, he's not like that.
那眞是有福氣
Well, what mighty good luck.
你有沒有...喜歡上他?
Are you, you know, fond of him?
我習慣了他
Well, I'm used to him.
他不在的時候 比如現在...
And when he's away, like now...
你想他嗎?      我不想他本人
Do you miss him?        I don't miss HIM.
我想念他帶來的世界
I miss the world that comes with him.
我也參與他的生意
I'm involved with his business.
莫名地讓人滿意
It's oddly satisfying.
你還有時間寫書嗎?
You still got time for your book?
沒我想象的多
Not as much as I'd hoped.
也許比平常還少了?
Perhaps got less to avenge now?
不 那倒沒有
No, I don't think that.
完全沒有
Not at all.
心軟了沒什麼不好 蘇糖
No harm in getting soft, Sugar.
我們都會的 只要有一點點機會
We all would, given half a chance.
酒鬼 喝呀
Rackers, buck up!
你看樣子更想大吃一頓
You look as though you'd rather be tucked up.
我凌晨四點纔從丹地回來
I got back from Dundee at four this morning!
弗拉泰里的歌聲會給你提神的
Flatelli will soon put the wind in your sails.
一會我們有計劃...讓你散心 別着急
We have plans to, er, revive you later, don't worry.
我們今早去了卡特韋太太那
We called on Mrs Castaway this morning.
有位幸運的先生把傳説中的蘇糖買走了
Some lucky gent has taken the legendary Sugar off the market -
我們還沒享受到她的魅力呢
before we'd had the benefit of her charms.
如果你眞找到包她的人
If you find out who's got her,
千萬告訴他我們很想分一杯羹
do tell him we're dying to have a bash.
我們打算去特魯里街看看雙胞胎
Anyway, we thought a trip to the twins in Drury Lane.
我約了人 不去了
previous engagement.
你眞無聊 比爾
You are dull, Bill.
我很開心呀
But happy.
他瘋掉了
He's lost his mind.
你不是喝熏衣草香水了吧?
You haven't been drinking the lavender water?
不是每個人都能穿白的
Not everyone can wear white.
確實不是 拉克漢太太
No, indeed, Mrs Rackham.
必須夠瘦纔行
You have to be very thin.
你説她到底吃不吃飯的?
Do you think she ever eats?
走吧?
Shall we?
(威爾第「安魂曲」1874)
(Verdi's Requiem)
你覺得怎樣 艾格尼絲?
Your opinion, Agnes?
我沒感覺 我就想透透氣
I have no opinion. I'd merely like some air.
天啊 你眞憔悴
Oh, goodness, you do look peakish.
布利德樓夫人
Lady Bridgelow,
你對我的關心眞是僞善又噁心
your concern for me is false and poisonous.
你又肥又胖 下巴上還長毛
You are fat and your chin has hairs on it!
艾格尼絲?
Agnes?
克拉拉?
Clara?
你不能看我的臉
You must not look at me in the face.
你不該看見我
You're not supposed to see me.
眞的是你嗎?
Is it you?
我是來幫你的 艾格尼絲
I'm going to help you, Agnes,
可你不能看我的臉
but you must not look at my face.
威廉總説你是我的想象
William says you are a trick of my imagination.
我好髒
I am filthy.
我全髒了
I'm covered in filth.
站起來 站起來
Stand up, stand up.
圍上這個
Wrap this round you.
你的味道好熟悉
You smell familiar.
現在聽好
Now listen,
我要你從這走出去 向左轉
I need you to walk out of here and turn left.
我會守望着你 艾格尼絲 可我們必須保密
I'll be watching you, Agnes, but this must be our secret.
你明白嗎? 不然我會有麻煩的
Do you understand? Otherwise I could get into trouble.
天使也會有麻煩嗎?
Can angels get into trouble?
我們這種生物不該介入你們的世界
Creatures like us are not supposed to interfere in your world.
我在守望着你 記住
I'm watching you, remember.
走吧 不要停
Go on, keep moving.
眞想知道這麼晚你能去哪
I do wonder where you can be at this time of night.
克拉拉
Clara!
是我 威廉
It's me, William.
克拉拉呢?
Where's Clara?
就在外面 別怕
Just outside, don't worry.
你感覺怎樣 親愛的?
How do you feel now, dear?
像頂無主的帽子
Like a lost bonnet
順着一條暗河漂流
floating along a dark river.
你眞體諒人
You are so very understanding.
不 不
No, no.
我憐憫她
I pity her.
我們這些健康無恙的人
We who have uninterrupted health
要爲我們的好運感恩
must be thankful for our good fortune.
難怪我親愛的阿爾伯特總告訴我要感恩
Certainly my dear Albert always urged me to be thankful for it
當年他活着的時候
when he was alive.
哦 親愛的布利德樓夫人
Oh, my dear Lady Bridgelow.
我沒什麼好抱怨的
I should not complain.
我有兒子 也是阿爾伯特的骨肉
I have my son, in whom Albert lives on.
他們兩人非常相似
The resemblance is very strong.
相信等你有了兒子也會是這樣
I don't doubt it will be the same for you when you have a son.
一定會的
I dare say it will.
你找我姊姊?
You're visiting my sister?
對 她身體還好吧
yes. I trust she is well.
她身體當然不好
Of course she's not well.
動動腦子 老兄 別賴着不走勞她費神
Use your sense, man. Don't stay too long and tire her out.
你好像有點蒼白
You are perhaps a little pale.
外表沒什麼意義
Appearances mean so little.
我親愛的伯蒂當年總是紅潤健康
My dear Bertie appeared to be in the pink of health always,
結果他先走了 我還活着
yet he is gone and I remain.
我眞盼望好起來 亨利
Oh, I am so anxious to be well, Henry.
因爲沒有小孩要照顧
With no children to look after
我的精力都留給了慈善事業
I have saved all my juices for the cause.
我知道他們很感激
I know the cause is grateful.
日復一日 我飽受折磨
I sit here tormented knowing each day that passes
又一個女人墮入生命的罪惡
one more woman sinks into a life of unbridled vice.
福克斯太太
Mrs Fox,
我想告訴你我也開始在聖吉爾斯工作了
I want you to know that I have myself begun to work in St Giles.
你 亨利?       所以你可以放心休息
You, Henry?        So you must rest easy in the knowledge
會有人替你露面的
that a presence is maintained.
我知道你和我感受相同
I knew that you felt as I do.
是的
I do.
你好 先生
Hello, sir.
想要一個價廉物美的好姑娘嗎?
Want a nice girl, not expensive?
我只想和你聊聊
I wish only to talk with you.
很好 來我房間吧
Very good. Come to my house.
不 我就是那個意思
No, no, I mean what I say.
一個先令
A shilling,
只是聊聊
just to talk.
你寫下來有什麼用?
What you writing it down for?
我臨時代替我朋友
Oh, I am temporarily taking over the work of a dear friend
救濟社的工作
in the Rescue Society.
所以準備把細節一一彙報給她       很好
I intend to report back in every detail.        nice.
反正你付了一先令了 儘管問吧
Well, you've paid your shilling, don't be shy.
如果你不介意的話 卡羅萊
when, if you don't mind, Caroline,
你是什麼時候失去了貞操?
did you lose your virtue?
十六歲
Age 16.
給了我丈夫
To my husband.
給了你丈夫?
To your husband?
那也不算失掉了貞操
Ah, well then you did not lose your virtue.
所以你離開了他 或者被抛棄了?
So you must have left him, then, or been cast out?
他死了 先生
He died, sir.
之後我的小男孩也跟着走了
Then my little boy followed close behind.
眞的深表遺憾
I am deeply sorry.
所以這是你墮落的原因?
So, that is when you fell into this way of being?
不是墮落 是別無它選
I didn't fall, I was pushed.
孩子的藥錢還欠着醫生
Owed the doctor for the child's medicine.
是他安排我踏入這行的
He arranged my start in the profession.
醫生?
The doctor?
我明白了
I see.
好的 容我冒昧提出
Well, forgive me,
我認識一個大工廠主
I know a man who runs a great concern.
我可以爲你安排一份工作
I could arrange employment for you.
我有工作
I have employment.
一份你不會遭天譴的工作
Employment by which you would not risk damnation.
我有工作
I have employment!
你想讓我在血汗工廠透支健康
You want me to break my health in a dirty factory
領着一週兩先令 爲你朋友創造財富?
for two shillings a week to help your friend make his fortune?
一先令的談話時間結束了
Now, your shilling's long since up.
卡羅萊 你相信你擁有靈魂嗎?
Caroline! Do you believe you have a soul?
你有的 我都有
Anything you got, I got, too.
你不爲它擔心嗎?
Then don't you fear for it?
我沒什麼好擔心的
You know, I fear nothing much
因爲我愛過 也被愛過
because I've loved and I've been loved.
這不正是靈魂的含義嗎?
Ain't that what a soul's about?
哥哥?       我需要和你談談 威廉
Brother?        Oh, I need to talk to you, William.
我剛從伯明翰回來
I've only just returned from Birmingham
需要去瑪麗勒本見一個重要的人
and I've an important appointment I need to make in Marylebone.
我是來懺悔的...
It is a confession...
某種程度上
of sorts.
坐下吧 亨利
Sit down, Henry.
夫人
Ma'am.
(英格蘭銀行)
他打扮得衣冠楚楚 超凡脱俗
He dresses it up as spiritual poppycock, of course,
事實上亨利戀愛了 卻拉不下臉承認
but the fact is that Henry's on heat and too priggish to admit it.
那你給他什麼建議?
So how did you advise him?
我告訴他 這些對福克斯的太太的感覺
I simply told him that the feelings he had for Mrs Fox
全是熱戀的典型症狀
bared all the hallmarks of infatuation
只能順其自然了
and they would simply run their course.
今天吸引我們的東西
What enthrals us today
明天也許什麼都不是了
may simply have no hold tomorrow.
的確
Indeed.
可憐的威廉
Poor William.
整個世界都塞給你麻煩
The whole world runs to you with its troubles.
只除了你
All except you.
我有什麼麻煩呢?
What troubles have I?
我是世上最幸運的女人
I am the luckiest woman alive.
我眞希望在這裏沈沈的睡去
I wish I could just fall asleep here.
好啊
Well, do.
我明天必須早起
I have to be up early tomorrow.
必須去熏衣草田裏
I have to go into the lavender fields.
熏衣草田?
The lavender fields?
熏衣草眞正生長的地方?
Where the lavender actually grows?
可以帶我去嗎?
Won't you take me?
樂意之至
I would love nothing more.
不過...
But...
我明白
I understand.
可惜你沒有監護人
It's a shame you don't have a chaperone.
比如一位善良的老紳士來讓此行
Some kindly old gent to add a veneer of
看上去體面一些
respectability to the exercise.
我想撒尿
I need to pee.
把這裏當家 尿到褲子上吧
Pretend you're at home and do it in your pants.
眞是熱心腸
So kind-hearted.
六先令和威士忌 記得嗎?
Six shillings and whisky, remember?
享受陽光吧
Enjoy the sunshine.
他們説好幾週前開始修剪這些花叢了
They claim they've been pruning these bushes for weeks.
其實是昨天下午吧
Yesterday afternoon, more like.
眞不可思議
It really is magnificent.
比我想象的還要大
Bigger than I'd ever imagined.
如果來場大火 怎樣?
What a bonfire this'd make, eh?
事實上 我們在第五年的秋天會把它們燒掉
Actually, we do burn all the plants in their fifth autumn.
火焰中的香氣可以迷醉整個米査姆區
The blaze is fragrant enough to cause all of Mitcham to swoon.
我正在找你
I've been looking for you!
最多六個月 你就捲舖蓋走人了
Give it six months and you'll be out on your arse.
你不知道你在説什麼吧
You don't know what you're talking about.
髒東西纔不喝呢 是吧
Oh, don't let anything dirty pass your lips.
令人窒息的美
It is breathtaking.
如果我膝下有一個兒子的話
If only I had a son to leave it to.
親愛的威廉
Dear William.
新鮮的空氣 很適合你
It suits you, the fresh air.
下面又流血了
'Bleeding again, underneath.
我肯定這都是吃東西造成的
'I am certain it's caused by eating.
如果不吃飯 就不會流血了
'If I don't eat, I don't bleed,
可我會暈倒 他們會找科魯來
'but then I get faint and they summon Curlew.
我的天使呢?
'Where is my angel?
好久沒有見到她了
'I have not seen her in so long.
也許我不配擁有她
'Perhaps I have not deserved her.'
有些汙垢永遠也別想清除
Some stains you never get out.
謝謝
Thank you.
可以坐起來了
You may sit up.
恐怕得説一切並不理想
I'm afraid all is not as it should be.
你的子宮已經移位
Your womb has moved.
比應該在的地方高了 所以...
It's much higher than where it ought to be, which is...
拉克漢太太 你在看什麼特別的東西嗎?
Mrs Rackham, are you looking at anything in particular?
我在尋找東西 科魯醫生
I'm looking for something, Dr Curlew.
什麼?       一個信號
What?        A sign.
我建議艾格尼絲多關注家務
I suggest Agnes take more interest in the household.
接下來 她就眞的擦去地板了
Next thing I know, she's actually scrubbing.
科魯認爲她必須被監管起來
Curlew's adamant she must be secured.
不
No.
艾格尼絲去精神病院 那要她怎麼活
Surely Agnes would never survive an asylum.
我也告訴過他
I've told him that.
一模一樣
Exactly.
可怕的是 前一天她還和正常人一樣
Awful thing is one day she's normal as you or I
接着
and the next...
就會和天使招手
..she's waving at angels.
艾格尼絲患病多久了?
How long has Agnes been this way?
老實説
If I'm honest,
她的瘋狂從生孩子開始就萌芽了
her madness has blossomed since the child.
她流産了一個小孩?
Agnes lost a child?
不 孩子生下來了
No, we have a child.
你們有小孩?
You have?
是的
Yes.
不幸的是 是個女孩
A daughter, unfortunately.
索菲
Sophie.
很少見她
See very little of her.
匆匆瞟過幾眼 就被護士帶去教堂了
The odd glimpse as she's being swept off to church by her nurse.
又一個災難臨頭
another looming disaster.
克萊弗女士説索菲需要一個家庭教師
Miss Cleave claims that Sophie needs a governess.
八歳的小孩需要上學嗎?
Does a child of eight need schooling?
還是個女孩
A girl, too!
每週想多跟我要一先令罷了
Trying to bounce another shilling out of me a week,
毋庸置疑
I don't doubt.
我多麼渴望能和你住在一起
I wish for all the world I could live with you.
「喜樂」基督勸勉我們説「應當歡喜快樂」
Rejoice, Christ exhorts us, and be exceeding glad,
「因爲你們在天上的賞賜是大的」
for great is your reward in heaven
「在你們以前的先知 人也是這樣逼迫他們」
for so persecuted they the prophets which were before you.
「你們是世上的鹽」
Ye are the salt of the earth,
「鹽若失了味」
but if the salt have lost his savour,
「怎能叫他再鹹呢?」
wherewith shall it be salted?
「以後無用」
It is thenceforth good for nothing,
「不過丟在外面」(語出《馬太福音》5:12)
but to be cast out...
科魯醫生
Why, Dr Curlew.
亨利
Henry.
我今天收到了福克斯太太的信
I received a message from Mrs Fox today.
是嗎?
Indeed?
聽説她要被送去海邊養病了
I gather she is to be sent away to the coast to recover.
是的 她會去福克斯通
She is going to Folkestone, yes.
這倒不假
That much is true.
你知道她會在那裏待多久嗎?
Do you have you any idea how long she'll be there?
以我對這個病的瞭解
I imagine, given my experience of the disease,
不會太久
not long at all.
最多幾個月
A couple of months at most.
她會去這麼久?
She'll be gone so long?
好吧...
Well, I...
她不在的時候 我要努力打發時間了
I shall strive to find ways to pass the time until she's back.
上帝啊 你們家族的男人腦子都有問題嗎?
Dear God, what is the matter with the men in your family?
你什麼都不明白嗎?
Do you understand nothing?!
我妹妹得肺結核快死了
My sister is dying of consumption.
再也不回來了
She'll never come back.
亨利?
Henry?
希望是你
I hoped it was you.
什麼耽擱你這麼久
But what kept you?
沒什麼能耽擱我
Nothing kept me.
等你的時間 實在太漫長了
Time passes so slowly for me when I am waiting for you.
福克斯太太
Mrs Fox,
我並不値得你這樣
I am not worthy.
哦 你値得...       不
Oh, but you are...        No!
我對你的感覺 使我不再懷疑
My feelings for you leave me in no doubt
我天生不是做傳教士的料
I am not cut out to be a clergyman.
亨利 別説了
Henry, stop.
看到你受此懲罰我很憤怒
I rage to see you punished in this way!
上帝遠比一個女人的疾病偉大
God is bigger than one woman's illness.
你會是最善良 最眞誠 最慷慨的牧師
You would make the kindest, sincerest, handsomest minister.
原諒我
Forgive me.
你今晚不和我們一起嗎 艾格尼絲?
Are you quite sure you won't join us this evening, Agnes?
我知道你很喜歡亨利
I know how fond you are of Henry.
科魯先生讓我別參加社交活動
Dr Curlew has advised against socialising.
我想他也説過別花太多時間
I think he also said it might be better not to spend
坐在窗戶邊 親愛的
so much time sitting at the window, dearest.
你不相信有天使 對嗎?
You don't believe in angels, do you?
是的 不相信
No, I don't.
你誰都不相信 除了威廉·拉克漢
You don't believe in anything except William Rackham.
她快死了 比爾
She's dying, Bill!
不 她服用新葯後更荒謬敏感了
No, she's absurdly highly strung and on new medication.
福克斯太太快死了
Mrs Fox is dying.
他哥哥説沒希望了
Her brother says there's no hope.
她的眼神看穿我的靈魂 比爾
She stares into my soul, Bill.
她乞求的眼神       你們倆...
Those imploring eyes.        You two had...
關係發展迅速
grown surprisingly close.
她的胸口起伏
Her breast heaves.
喘息的抓住我的手
She pants and clutches at my hand.
有你在身邊安慰 她眞幸運 亨利
How lucky she is to have you to comfort her, Henry.
感覺像...
It is as if...
感覺她還想向我要什麼東西
As if she wants something more from me.
一點也不驚訝
It's not surprising.
我問自己一遍又一遍
I ask myself over and over and over
她要我給他什麼?
what is it she thinks I can give her?
你不是開玩笑吧?
Are you serious?
我向主禱告 從早到晚
I have prayed for guidance, night and day!
可憐啊 亨利
For pity's sake, Henry!
她想讓你好好看着她
She wants you to give her a good seeing to!
她想和你好好做愛 亨利
She wants you to give her a good fucking, Henry!
你是禽獸嗎...?
What sort of a creature...?
這屋子再也呆不下去了
I can't stay in this house.
別再折磨她了 亨利
Stop tormenting her, Henry!
如果她眞的快死了 讓她最後歡愉一次吧
If she really is dying, just let her feel pleasure at least once!
威廉 怎麼回事?
William, what is it?
我讓馬車伕黎明就來
I've asked Cheesman to come at dawn.
我們直接去熏衣草田
We will leave for the lavender fields straightaway.
那...       爲什麼要管別人想什麼?
What about...        What do I care what people think?
這他媽是我的熏衣草田 我的生意
It's my damn lavender field, it's my damn business!
我厭倦了被那些白癡評判
I'm sick of being judged by fools
那些對世界一無所知的人
who have no idea how the world works,
那些人之所以滿口道德良心
who have the luxury of a clear conscience
都因爲騎在我這種骯髒俗人的頭上
because I pay for it on a dirty, daily basis!
《聖經》
Holy Bible
福克斯太太?
Mrs Fox?
你氣色眞好
You look so well.
當然了 亨利
Of course, Henry.
我已經去天堂了
I'm in heaven.
等不及想讓你也來了
I can't wait for you to join me.
我想和你一起
I want to join you.
我很想...
I want to...
可我們沒有結婚
but we are not married.
天堂裏沒有嫁娶 亨利
There is no marriage in heaven, Henry.
《馬可福音》12章25節
Mark 12:25.
福克斯太太...
Mrs Fox...
如果我和你住在一起
If only I could live with you.
該是多大的幫助啊
You are such a help to me.
我希望能多幫助你一些
I wish I could help you more.
其實不只是亨利和艾格尼絲
It's not only Henry and Agnes.
整棟房子都失控了
The entire household is out of control.
艾格尼絲的女僕公然蔑視我
Agnes' maid treats me with open contempt,
克萊弗小姐也終於遞了辭呈
Miss Cleave has finally handed notice,
我只能再找家庭教師了
so now I have to find a new governess.
你説和我住在一起是認眞的?
Are you serious about living with me?
當然是認眞的
Of course I am...
但這不可能
..but it's impossible.
我不能作爲家庭教師 和你住在一起嗎?
Could I not, in fact, live with you as your new governess?
拉克漢先生       你不是認眞的吧?
Mr Rackham!        You're not serious?
抱歉       拉克漢先生
I'm sorry.        Mr Rackham!
我只是想...
I only thought...
拉克漢先生
Mr Rackham!
先生
Sir!
你快去 先生 馬上
You're wanted, sir, at once!
是你的哥哥
It's your brother!
第二集 終
謝謝觀賞